<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Refracted Pixels</title>
    <link>http://gabem.me/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Refracted Pixels</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 12:04:02 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://gabem.me/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my new site</title>
      <link>http://gabem.me/blog/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 12:04:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gabem.me/blog/new-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago now, I was planning to attend my first ever &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gdconf.com/&#34;&gt;GDC&lt;/a&gt; and I
wanted to be as prepared as possible. I needed business cards, an up to date
resume, clever things on Twitter, and, of course, a web site with my portfolio.
Resume and Twitter gave me no trouble. And with help from my awesome spouse, I
was armed with really fucking rad business cards. The key problem: they
pointed to a domain completely devoid of content!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since the &lt;a href=&#34;http://thegabeproject.com/&#34;&gt;Geocities&lt;/a&gt; days, I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled with making a personal web site.
However, I never really had any content I considered useful enough to follow
through with it. This time, I had a pressing need for one, which led me to
decide that it was finally time to learn &lt;em&gt;How to Make a Real Web Site From
Scratch™&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a real honest attempt at it. I watched a 6 hour video to learn modern CSS
and HTML, all while diligently coding up the examples and doing every practice
problem. By the end of the course, I was ready. I had already chosen to make a
static web site using GitHub Pages and &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;a relatively new and awesome
static site framework&amp;mdash;I just had to get to work. So, with some more design
help from my spouse, I created a simple site that I was pretty pleased with:

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://gabem.me/images/old-site.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gabem.me/images/old-site.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Let us take a moment to appreciate the artisanal, jQuery-free HTML and CSS.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success! That is, until I looked at my list of features and improvements that I
wanted for it. With my rudimentary knowledge of web development and ambitious
goals for the site, I had spent dozens of hours researching and working on tech
and less than one writing content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GDC came and went. I planned to work on the site, but could quite never find
the time. Slowly, days turned to weeks turned to months. When I finally got a
chance to work on the web site, I was embarrassed by how empty I&amp;rsquo;d left it! So
much so that I put up a &amp;ldquo;Coming Soon&amp;rdquo; page, in hopes that it would encourage me
to do more work:

&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://gabem.me/images/under-construction.png&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://gabem.me/images/under-construction.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Well that&amp;#39;s a step back.&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More time passed yet the page stayed the same. Luckily for me, in the
intervening years, Hugo had evolved a theming system with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;large gallery of
themes&lt;/a&gt; to choose from. Awww, yissss! It was time to give up my dreams of
hand-crafting a web site and use someone else&amp;rsquo;s theme. I looked at several
&lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-mdl/&#34;&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/academic/&#34;&gt;themes&lt;/a&gt;, but chose to go with &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/future-imperfect/&#34;&gt;Hugo Future Imperfect&lt;/a&gt;. This was a
great way to build a static web site! In a few hours I was able to &lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt;
a new repository, configure the theme, write some content, and push the site
to GitHub Pages. Which you are reading right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it was a long, meandering path to get to this point, but I am very happy
with the results. I think we can all agree that the moral of this story is to
never do something from scratch that you need done before next week. Especially
if you&amp;rsquo;ve no idea what you&amp;rsquo;re getting into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Many thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://jpescador.com/&#34;&gt;Julio Pescador&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for finally enabling me to make a
simple, beautiful web site with little fuss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>