<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Refracted Pixels</title>
    <link>http://gabem.me/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Refracted Pixels</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 16:39:37 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gabem.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping a Clean Home with XDG User Dirs</title>
      <link>http://gabem.me/blog/xdg-user-dirs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 16:39:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gabem.me/blog/xdg-user-dirs/</guid>
      <description>For my birthday last year, I decided that the time had come. Time for me to finally purchase a new laptop to replace my aging 2013 MacBook Air (RIP). Apple had slowly pushed me back to Linux, so I went with the excellent Lenovo X1 Carbon, whose 5th generation had come out earlier in 2017. It arrived nearly a month later. When the weekend came around, I flashed a USB drive with the latest Arch Linux Live image, rolled up my sleeves, and got to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Fail, Episode 2: Procedural Generation</title>
      <link>http://gabem.me/blog/mechanical-fail-episode-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 17:13:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gabem.me/blog/mechanical-fail-episode-2/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today, my friend and collaborator Jonathon Wallace published the second episode of our podcast, Mechanical Fail! I completely forgot to post about us starting the series, so I&amp;rsquo;ll expand on it some more here.
Mechanical Fail is a way for us to discuss elements of games that we like or dislike, hoping to distinguish how and why certain games appeal to us more than others. There&amp;rsquo;s no set schedule just yet, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting about new episodes here and on my Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my new site</title>
      <link>http://gabem.me/blog/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 12:04:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gabem.me/blog/new-site/</guid>
      <description>A couple of years ago now, I was planning to attend my first ever GDC and I wanted to be as prepared as possible. I needed business cards, an up to date resume, clever things on Twitter, and, of course, a web site with my portfolio. Resume and Twitter gave me no trouble. And with help from my awesome spouse, I was armed with really fucking rad business cards. The key problem: they pointed to a domain completely devoid of content!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>